ANIS MEMON

13 Lapointe Street, Winooski, VT 05404 | 802.355.6227 | anismemon096@gmail.com linkedin.com/in/anis-memon-04441518a

FULL-STACK WEB DEVELOPER

I am an emerging full-stack web developer, committed to my new career direction building on years of work experience in the fields of translation and education. My critical thinking skills honed through the detailed analysis of literary texts and my process-oriented, results-based approach developed through curriculum design have prepared me for the challenges and opportunities in the field of web design. I am a quick, methodical, yet flexible learner; I work well both independently and as a member of task-driven small teams and have extensive cross-cultural communication experience.

TECHNICAL SKILLS SUMMARY

RELEVANT EXPERIENCE

Inu Labs (developer) Fairfax, VT May 2020 – present

Data-gathering technology initiative.

Developer (Data Dog scalable mobile app and administrative web tool)

Simplifying data collection through a single, scalable mobile app that can be formatted for a host of data-collection needs.

Streamlining old code to facilitate scalability

Code for BTV (informal intern)

Burlington, VT

Mar 2020 - present

Local Brigade of national nonprofit Code for America.

Developer (Green Up app, Can't Stop Vermont)

Worked as an integral development member on the Green Up app. One of the principle initiators of the Can't Stop Vermont project.

- Completed outstanding code, fixed bugs, managed databases, tested
- Acted as liaison between Code for BTV and Green Up in matters relating to the Green Up administrative portal
- Currently developing the scope of a Can't Stop Vermont urgent update app as a response to the COVID-19 pandemic

Audubon Vermont Huntington, VT Mar 2020 – Apr 2020

Nonprofit conservation organization whose mission is to protect birds and the places they need, today and tomorrow.

Developer (Capstone Project – Burlington Code Academy)

Worked with the Vermont Peregrine Tracking Project to develop a mobile-friendly data collection portal for their 50 volunteer observers to use in the field, store the data, and provide real-time dashboard reporting.

• Used full MERN stack development

OTHER WORK EXPERIENCE

University of Vermont – Romance Languages

Burlington, VT

2009 - 2019

The largest language department at UVM, offering Spanish, French and Italian.

Lecturer (Full Time, Permanent Role)

Provided elementary and intermediate language instruction inspiring students to learn to communicate in real-world situations in French, Italian, and English (TESOL), from basic communication to advanced, academic settings. Conducted all classes (25-30 students per class) in target language – even at the elementary level. Assessed student progress through written and oral evaluation. Prepared all course materials (e.g. daily assignments, in-class lecture materials, assessments, homework, etc.).

- Offered four highly-motivated students of Italian the opportunity to skip their regular daily language lessons in favor of targeted group lessons with me (one semester)
- Member of the executive council for the Department of Romance Languages and Linguistics
- Participated in two departmental hiring searches (department chair and one-year faculty appointment)

Various Employers

WI, CA, IL, and Italy

1995 - present

Freelance Translator, Data Analyst, Customer Service roles, Environmental Canvasser (Greenpeace), and Language Instructor

EDUCATION

Full-stack Developer Certificate Full-stack development, JavaScript, CSS,	Burlington Code Academy, Burlington, VTApril 2020 HTML, React, and Git
Graduate Certificate in TESOL	St. Michael's College, Colchester, VT2017
Best practices in practical language acquinew American groups and one-on-one w	isition. Focus on formative assessment. Experience teaching and advising riting evaluation.
DALF, C2	Centre International d'Études Pédagogiques (CIEP)2007
Ph.D. & M.A. Comparative Literature	University of Michigan, Ann Arbor, MI
, , ,	sis focused on the introduction of popular language into narrative, and written (literary) language as a way of expanding the expressive

COMMUNITY & MEMBERSHIPS

Code for BTV	Volunteer	2020 – present
American Translator's Association	Member	2018 – present
Winooski French Conversation Group	Founding Leader	2016 – 2017
United Academics (UVM Faculty Union)	Delegate, College of Arts and Sciences	2014 – 2016
	Member, Bargaining Team	2014 – 2016
	Department Representative	2013 – 2014
French & Italian Conversation Groups	Founding Leader	2010 – 2015
Witness For Peace, Havana, Cuba	Member, American Delegation	2005
Volunteers for Peace, Bobbio, Italy	On-the-Spot Translation Services	1994